Alexander H. W. Grant

Portland OR

☐ (603) 667 5542 • ☑ alex.h.w.grant@gmail.com • ☑ grantal.net linkedin.com/in/grantal • github.com/grantal

Summary

Web developer with extensive experience working successfully in small teams to make large-scale Django apps.

Technical Skills

o Python, C, Java, Javascript, HTML, bash, SML/NJ, Go, CSS, C#, C++, SQL, Ruby, Markdown, R, dplyr, ggplot2 o vim, Git, Github, SVN, Travis CI, Django, Flask, Node.js, RoR, Pytest, Selenium, Jquery, LATEX, WebGL

Education

Reed College Portland, OR

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science and Mathematics

Aug 2014–May 2018

React, three.js

Coursework included Cryptography, Computer Systems, and Graphics.

Dartmouth College Hanover NH

Community Student Sept 2013–Mar 2014

Completed four undergraduate computer science classes while in high-school.

Projects

The source code for these projects is presented at grantal.net/projects.

grantal.net

Personal Project Sept 2018-Present

Updating my personal website to show my love for 3D graphics while maintaining usability. Deployed to github pages.

TI4Calc Vue.js, RGraph, Bootstrap

Open Source Jul 2018-Present

Project started by alpha-mouse on github. It is a webapp that predicts the outcomes of battles in the board game *Twilight Imperium*. I am currently improving the mobile experience of the app. Deployed to github pages.

Backpack-Builder React

Personal Project May 2018

A React website that lets you select backpacking equipment and gives you the total weight of that equipment. Deployed using github pages.

WebGL-Sandpiles

JavaScript, WebGL, Pengiun, jQuery

Reed College Undergraduate Thesis

Sept 2017-May 2018

The Abelian sandpile model is the simplest representation of self-organized criticality. As such, the model can be used to explore self-organized critical systems in both mathematics and physics. I developed a WebGL 3D simulation of the Abelian sandpile model as my independent research project for my senior thesis. Deployed the simulation to github pages and to Reed's static site hosting. Developed a function approximating the identity on a circular sandpile with R and produced data visualizations of the approximation.

Tiger Compiler C++, Catch2, Flex, Bison

Reed College Coursework

Feb-May 2018

Worked cooperatively with three other students in the upper-level class "Compiler Design" to develop a compiler for a functional language. Implemented automated tests at each stage of compilation using the Catch2 framework.

Paneity Django, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Bootstrap

Reed College Software Design Studio

Mav-Aug 2017

Worked with a team of four students to develop a website for connecting tutors to students. Created automated unit tests for the website using Django's test runner. Deployed to a Linux VM with Apache.

django-private-chat

Django, Websockets, Asyncio

Open Source Jun 2017

Ported this project, which is maintained by the Bearle team, to Paneity. Solved issues with tests running on Travis CI. Fixed the example code.

Kronos

Flask, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Bootstrap

Reed College Software Design Studio

May-Aug 2016

Worked with a partner to make a website for scheduling oral defenses of senior theses. Made a suite of tests with PyTest.

Vrfy

Django, PostgreSQL, Docker, Celery, Bootstrap

Reed College Software Design Studio

May-Aug 2015

Worked on a two-person team to create a web application to grade computer-programming assignments. Made automated tests with Django's test runner. Deployed to a Linux VM with Apache.

Test Editor

Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, jQuery

Tom Tom

Jun-Aug 2014

Web application deployed to a Windows machine that provided software testers a single interface in which to evaluate all elements of their jobs.

Work Experience

C2 Education Beaverton OR

SAT Math Tutor Jun 2018–Present

Worked individually with students to improve their mathematical skills. Several got perfect scores in practice tests for SAT Math section and Mathematics Level 2 Subject Test.

Centennial High School

Gresham OR

Tutor Mar–May 2018

As part of the Schools Uniting Neighborhoods program, assisted students after school with their mathematics homework. Developed interpersonal skills; empathy, honesty, and humor, to succeed as tutor.

Reed College Portland OR

Van Driver Sept 2015-Mar 2018

Supported the academic community by driving a fifteen-passenger van for physical education classes.

Trip Leader Aug 2018

As part of Reed's orientation program, lead a group of incoming Freshman on a backpacking excursion to the Cascade Mountains.

Peer Tutor, Philosophy 201 Logic

Sept 2016-May 2018

Nominated by a professor to help other students with Logic.

Software Design Studio Intern

Jan 2015-Dec 2017

Collaborated with other students on various Python–based WebApps for the school. Communicated effectively to meet project deadlines. Worked nights and weekends to keep the projects running, several of which were adopted by Reed College. Maintained the software after their adoption. These efforts are described in the "Projects" section.

Web Support Services Intern

Sept 2014-Jan 2015

Created a mock scheduler with JavaScript for the class-list website.

TomTom Lebanon NH
Intern Jun-Aug 2014

Following agile-development principles, created an Express.js-based website to display and to edit test-job information from a PostgreSQL database.

Hannaford Supermarket West Lebanon NH

Center Store Associate

Jul-Oct 2013

Responsible for stocking shelves and facing products.

Interests

- Sports
- Cycling Backpacking
- Resistance training
- Strategy board games
- Twilight Imperium Diplomacy